Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/steven-wong-design (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Illustration

Photoshop

Digital Painting

Languages

English (Full Professional)

Steven Wong

Product Design at Facebook

United States

Summary

Well-rounded designer with visual and product design experience. I value the creative process and have a holistic approach to design. I collaborate really well with other designers, marketers and across other departments to find the best solution. I am well versed in the core Adobe tools (Illustrator, Photoshop, Indesign), Sketch, print design and animation (After Effects). I have experience developing a visual brand and standardizing it across the company. I work at a fast pace but take the time to really understand who and what I am designing for. I have a passion for what I do and a hunger to learn more.

Experience

Facebook
Product Designer
October 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months)

Walmart eCommerce

4 years 4 months

Lead Designer

March 2021 - October 2021 (8 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Senior Product Designer

February 2019 - March 2021 (2 years 2 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Product Designer

July 2017 - February 2019 (1 year 8 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

SafetyCulture Pty Ltd Visual Designer July 2016 - July 2017 (1 year 1 month)

San Francisco Bay Area

Provided all designs and creative materials for the marketing team of the 100+ employee startup. My role included designing the website, landing pages, email campaigns, and graphics for social media and the blog. I also owned all promotional and event collateral such as brochures, flyers, banners, and booths. Owned design and distribution for all company merchandise, both for internal and customer-facing applications. Collaborated with the product design team to provide feedback on designs for new features and improved UI / UX.

- Implemented company's first comprehensive creative process that successfully streamlined projects, reduced wasted time, and cut down back and forth communication.
- Developed branding guidelines for the company with a customer base of over 100,000 users.
- Redesigned company website and support site for desktop and mobile responsive.
- Acted as the sole design resource for the company and provided design direction in collaboration with the marketing team to increase brand awareness.

Swonglllustrated Freelance Artist 2013 - 2017 (4 years)

Create various designs and illustrations for clients. Projects include ad banners, page layouts, logo design, poster design, illustration, apparel design, character design, storyboarding, and sketching.

Cloudability
Product Designer
January 2016 - July 2016 (7 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Provided creative solutions for projects that covered new features, customer pain points, and improving user experience and functionality for the cloud cost management tool. Owned user interactions for new and existing pages, utilizing a combination of animation software and prototyping tools. Built out prototypes for customer demos and user testing. Worked on improving the customer journey by contributing to the redesign of new user onboarding and account management. Also contributed to designing for the company internally, creating custom signage, illustrations and improvements to the support site.

DataHero

1 year

Visual Designer August 2015 - January 2016 (6 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

DataHero is self-service cloud BI that allows any user to quickly connect to cloud services without the help of an IT team. This is data analysis reimagined from the ground up, focusing on intuitive design and experience to enable non-analysts and analysts alike.

Designed for the marketing department to help increase inbound/outbound traffic and brand awareness. My duties included creating SEO and SEM banners, landing pages, custom presentations, social media design, promotional and blog content. The promotional material included print collateral and animated videos for events such as Hubspot's annual Inbound conference. For the blog, I provided photography editing and illustrations for custom banners, as well as designed infographics to complement the content.

Freelance Designer

February 2015 - August 2015 (7 months)

DataHero is self-service cloud BI that allows any user to quickly connect to cloud services without the help of an IT team. This is data analysis reimagined from the ground up, focusing on intuitive design and experience to enable non-analysts and analysts alike.

Create ad banners and graphics for internal as well as web use.

Ringling College of Art and Design

2 years 10 months

Concept Artist / Visual Designer
January 2012 - May 2013 (1 year 5 months)

Developed 2D graphics and art, props, and character for my visual development thesis:

- · Critically researched and designed location props and environments based on details from the rain forests of Borneo.
- · Established characters and their expressions and gestures that reflect their written counterparts.
- · Designed storyboards to describe a particular scene in the story and establish mood.

- · Wrote out summaries of each chapter for the corresponding children's storybook.
- · Designed concept art book using Adobe InDesign that included all sketches, final art, and story.

Fitness Assistant August 2010 - May 2013 (2 years 10 months)

Ringling Business Playdoh Project Visual Development Artist / Team Leader 2012 - 2013 (1 year) Ringling College of Art and Design

Collaborated with team of four classmates composed of different majors to design a new product for Hasbro's Playdoh brand that targets a different audience of consumers in conjunction with Ringling's business department

- · Provided concept art for characters, props, environments and packaging graphics that showcased the new product and its capabilities in detail
- · Presented new product in a marketing pitch to Hasbro's department heads

Education

Ringling College of Art and Design
Bachelor of Fine Arts (BFA), Illustration · (2009 - 2013)

Seminole Ridge Community High School